All right, welcome everyone. Day two
Atlas. We have a great talks today. Um,
session one is going to be enterprise AI
and our first speaker is Sunnita Verma
with ironclad. Welcome Sunnita.
Thank you very much. Yeah,
>> good morning everyone. Uh I hope you had
a wonderful time yesterday, enjoyed the
sessions. Um my name is Sunita WHMA. I
am CTO at Ironclad. Uh prior to coming
at Ironclad, um I was I spent almost 18
years at Google building and um
deploying AI technology at scale for
various use cases. Um, so I'm going to
talk about uh I'm going to make a claim
and I'm going to be use the next 10 to
15 minutes validating or supporting that
claim with some of the data that we have
seen. And my claim is that um and
actually the video that was playing
beforehand sort of set it up properly
very appropriately for me. The adoption
of AI in enterprises is not stalling
because the technology is not working or
is not there. It's stalling because of
other reasons. And one of the other
reasons tends to be processes, culture
and so on. And the question I think we
all want to ask is why should you care?
Why do you want to care about whether
the technology gets deployed in an
enterprise or not? And my claim to that
is
all the good work, all the great work
that we heard about yesterday that we're
going to hear about today
needs to deliver value otherwise it's
all for a not. So the who are the
eventual users of this technology it's
going to be all the people who live in
thousands and thousands of companies
that exist around us.
So I want to start with the story. um
nine months ago which is approximately
like a month or two after I had joined
Ironclad um we were having a discussion
about features and I deliberately ran an
experiment there. I asked two different
engineers for an estimate of what it'll
take to build that feature
and guess what I found? I found such
diverging
um amount of time in estimates that it
gave me a pause. I'm like what's going
on here? And the when I dug into it, one
of the things I realized it's actually
less about the seniority of the engineer
or familiarity of the engineer with the
codebase. The difference was one of the
engineer was AI pled and understood how
to use the technology and work with the
technology and steer the technology and
so on. And the other was using AI
technology mainly as a chatbot but felt
that they already had mastered the
technology.
And so I had a choice to make at that
point. I knew that the rate at which the
technology is advancing, this gap is
going to get compounded between people
and I could actually accept to have a
twospeed engineering organization or I
could do something about it.
So one of the things I stepped back and
thought about is why is it that people
feel that they have mastered the
technology when they actually haven't?
And at least my assertion is in the
previous technologies whether it's
mobile whether it's cloud when you had
an error the error was obvious to you.
The technology sort of pushed back and
you knew you had to fix the error. You
knew you had to learn what's going on or
what's going wrong before you could make
progress. But with AI because the
interface is natural language
just by talking to it you sort of feel
you already know what you're doing.
without realizing that the outputs need
to be validated, the outcome needs to be
validated. So it actually just it's a
very different mental model that you
have to use with this technology. And
yes, many of you sitting in the audience
may say, "Oh, I already knew that." But
there is a huge workforce out there that
is not in the same mindset and a lot of
people sitting here. So it's if we want
the technology to be adopted by that set
of people it's important that we do
something about it.
So one of the things I also learned from
lot of other companies talking to a lot
of other companies is and these are big
fortune 500 sometimes fortuneund
companies most of the companies say oh
we'll enable our engineers and I think
that's a myopic view to take because you
enable one function but then you create
bottlenecks in other part of your
organization so one of the very
deliberate thing we did at ironclad
right from the beginning is we will
enable everyone at the same time yes
some people were already pretty AID and
they felt that they were not they didn't
need this but we were very clear that we
want engineering product and design to
work together to get enabled together
so one of the goals we set for oursel I
set for the team is we want to make sure
we are a company where building with AI
and building AI is not a bespoke act for
certain people everybody can actually
build it everybody can build with the
technology So three principles we
basically said there are just going to
be a you know halo set of people on this
side that are doing AI and then they
pull everybody along with them. that
hard parts of making sure the outcome
validation the eval the eval harnesses
everything is going to be through
tooling so that so that everyone gets
the benefit of it at the same time and
then it's not going to be more like hey
only certain top people get to use AI
and nobody else everybody has to use AI
and everybody will use AI so we
basically started with these principles
and what I did was um I leveraged one of
the pro things we had coming up so I was
just 3 months into the company at that
time we had a hackathon coming up in
December 2025. So I'm talking eight
months back which is an eternity in AI.
Um so December 2025 we had a hackathon
coming up and I wanted to make sure that
the team actually comes prepared with AI
in this hackathon and we get we
basically see AI build related outcomes
from the hackathon. So I created a
20-day program prior to the hackathon
that we ran prior to the hackathon to
basically do the skill building across
the organization and we are at a much
different place as a company now but
this is basically eight months back
day one uh because I built technology
I'm very familiar with the technology I
actually took classes for the whole team
for and I think we allowed it anybody
across the company to be able to join
those classes. So I took classes on
basically LLM fundamentals, how LLM
works under the hood, how to think about
context, incontext learning, prompt
optimization, tuning, evaluations and so
on. And then for the next 20 days, for
rest of the two to 20 days, one engineer
every day will basically come and uh
talk about how they built with what they
built with the technology, how they
built with the technology, how the what
problems they ran into and what
learnings they took away from it. And we
kept the sort of the momentum going
through slack channels, through
interactions, through you know um sort
of impromptu gettogethers that engineers
wanted to do among their themselves. And
so we ran the whole program in 20 days
and come hackathon we actually got like
huge amount of participation. We got lot
of people building capabilities,
building new things that I didn't think
that the team was basically team could
build but they surprised me
significantly
on a positive side. So fluency wise we
were there as a company at that point
and one of the things I was expecting to
see out of it and this is now we are
talking about January 2026 again still
seven to eight months away from where we
are today. So I'm just telling you a
story. This is not the state of the
company where we are today. Um January
2026 the the the sort of like the
feature development part didn't sort of
take off as as at the same rate as I had
thought. And again I'm like okay what
happened? I thought we had already
upskilled everybody. I should be seeing
we should be seeing like all this
building happening in the product in in
in experimentation. We were already
there but in the product we should be
seeing all this building happening. So
what's what's what's going wrong
and the and I realize it is actually
Andel's law and what Andel's law says is
you update one part of the process but
now the parts of the process that you
didn't touch actually become the
bottleneck and one of the things I
realized is um yes we were building
every function was building AI and
building with AI but we hadn't we had
not shifted did the process at all and
we were still following a waterfall
model of development where product will
do its research they'll hand it off to
UX and then it'll come to the engineer
and engineer will basically get done
really quickly and then most of the time
they'll be just waiting for answers from
the product team I'm like oh okay so
this is actually where we need to fix
the the we need to actually change our
approach
so we basically tweaked the process we I
already talked about education being the
infrastructure
And um part of that education being the
infrastructure is building a shared
lexicon, building shared tooling,
building harnesses and making sure that
there are common systems for context
management, rag, memory across the
board. So we are basically brought all
the organizational memory into a single
system. But I think the it's the process
part of the shifting that actually was
very interesting. So what we do now is
when trying to build something the
relevant people will come together early
on they'll basically get together
they'll discuss the problem they'll
debate the problem they'll come up with
a solution they'll iterate on the
solution and they will memorialize the
solution as either a markdown or a
notion page and I don't know if any of
you attended professor Ian Stoya's um
talk yesterday one of the things he was
talking about is why the outcomes from
AI are not what people expected it to
be. Part of it is under specification of
the requirements
and having everybody come together in
the early stage of the process allows us
to flesh out those requirements right in
the beginning before handing off that
fleshed out work to an agent to execute
to an AI agent to execute. I'm not
saying we are perfect there but I think
we have seen the benefit of
specifying like clearly specifying the
constraints and the boundaries and the
solution space of the problem before
giving it to an agent to execute and we
are seeing really good outcome and I'll
show you some data around that as well.
The second the last but not the least
thing is basically we have created tools
and guard rails that ensure so obviously
there are code review agents but there
are just lot of skills that we have
built to ensure that the quality of the
outcome that is produced by these agents
especially on the coding side meets the
requirements uh the standards that we
have in our company and so that nobody
has to wonder whether their agent is
doing the right thing or not.
So where are we as a company? Um so what
I told you was up to January 2026 AI
space moves really fast and we move
really fast. We moved really fast to to
keep pace with it or to outpace it
sometimes actually. So we have created
an agent framework and this is sort of a
cartoon diagram. I I omitted some of the
deep technical details from here. This
we have created an agent framework which
basically enables everyone to anyone to
create an agent really quickly. Um and
it's based on agent SDK from OpenAI and
um AI SDK from Versell connected to all
the frontier models. We we have also
started tuning actually our own models.
So some of those models are also getting
hooked up behind these behind these
agents and we built all the other
infrastructure around it for continuous
context optimization, memory management,
continuous evas um prompting uh and and
so on. So this is the this is sort of
the framework that the whole company
uses now to create agents.
We've also basically create automated
evals in large parts of our system. Um
and evals tend to be one of those
underspecified things or under invested
things that people use. So we do have um
LLM judges that are actually evaluating
the output that is being produced by a
lot of these um agents and then they
give it to an evaluation agent which
then compares it against a rubric and
till it's till it basically decides that
yes the eval is actually coming very
close to the rubric. It'll keep running
those continuous evals without involving
any of our engineers in the process. So
once the engineer once a sub something
has been built, reviewed and checked in,
it basically goes through this
evaluation process automatically.
We've also built our own code generation
harness. We evaluated everything
actually out there. We basically
evaluated Codex harness. We evaluated um
Claude's hardness. And so what we did
was none of them were coming close to
what we wanted to build. So we basically
took them as benchmarks some of the open
source ones as sort of the substrate and
we built our own code generation harness
on top of it. Um we are using temporal
and temporal was here yesterday so shout
out. Um
so what people now do and by the way our
product managers are also coding now
because it's just so easy to do uh the
right thing. Um so anybody can actually
interface with this harness. they can
actually give it a job to do. Uh whether
it is a UI that you want built, whether
it's a backend part of the service that
you want built, uh whether it is um
whether it is any other part of the code
you want written, you can give it to the
harness. The harness actually spins up a
VM. It basically sets up the whole
environment almost equivalent to a
production environment in that VM,
generates the code in that VM, tests the
code in that VM and produces a review
ready PR that can then get reviewed by
either humans or um a coding uh a review
agent.
This is sort of what the web interface
for our harness looks like. I've
deliberately sort of made the colors
weaker because there are some things
that I didn't that are more proprietary
to us. So basically um this is the
hardness that people use. It's in dog
food right now and uh we are getting
really really good results from it. Um
we've also delivered a lot of value in
the product. By the way, um, uh, as I
said, we are a legal tech, commercial
legal product. Almost all the companies
in Silicon Valley are customers,
including the Frontier Labs. And so
there are a lot of products that are
that are agents that live in our product
today. And those agents are act like
turning real running contracts which are
billions of dollars of value that is
running through them at this point. Um,
nine months later, this is where we are
like it's a very different place for me
as well as as a company. Um these are
more engineering statistics and by the
way the drops you see at the end of the
curve is incomplete data. It's not that
you know we've suddenly become we are
suddenly back to square one kind of
thing. So our execution velocity is just
very very different than what I saw um a
year ago. Just one last thing I want to
leave you with um it's not that this is
something that proprietary to us.
Actually one of our customers reached
out to us. It's a Fortune 100 company
that reached out to us and wanted to run
the same program us.
We didn't design the program to run it
for other people but you know it's a
customer um enterprise customer and a
big customer. So we just wanted to make
sure that we are able to support them as
well. We ran the program for the
customer and the outcomes were very very
similar. The customers are also seeing
acceleration in the work on their side.
And again, uh, I know time is up, just
one second. Um, I think if any of you
attended Andrew Ing's fireside chart
chat yesterday, one of the things he was
talking about, he's worried about lack
of education or lack of investment in
education by a lot of people building AI
because that is going to become one of
the barriers to adoption. And so we are
sort of seeing I'm giving you a data
point from our experience in support of
that claim. And we are saying something
very similar that you know education is
an important component of getting AI
deployed in enterprises. Um just a
little bit about ironclad very quickly.
Um as I said we are almost all Silicon
Valley companies are customers for us
including all the frontier labs. The
ones we have logo we I'm putting the
names down at the bottom. Um have
thousands of customers and so on. Um
that's it from my side. Uh I am going to
be around um in networking sessions or
breaks if you want to chat with me. And
this is my LinkedIn in case you want to
follow. Thank you very much for your
attention.
All right. Thank you, Senita. Next up,
we have Ori Gosian with AI21.
All right,
let's uh wait for the slides.
Okay, so uh good morning everyone. It's
really great to be here. Uh my name is
Ory Gosh. I'm the co-founder and CEO of
AI21.
Uh AI21 is um an AI lab based in Tel
Aviv. Uh super excited to be here and
tell you about our work around uh
self-optimizing agents. And uh so today
we'll speak about um you know kind of
these self- evvolving AI systems
uh why it's needed uh why it's hard and
and why now. And um and I mean you know
um the time is now. I mean we all uh see
the challenges in in the industry. We
will speak about it and uh of course uh
my I can I can say personally for myself
my wife is asking from me uh this
feature all the time and uh I'm probably
still in the early beta version.
So um
uh so so uh yeah let's so in in in the
past few months we've seen uh many of
these um AI system actually shift from
experimentation to production. uh we're
still very early uh in this uh in this
journey of AI adoption but we're seeing
still we're we're seeing systems that
are now being uh actually deployed at
scale and this introduces new set of
challenges um and the most obvious one
is to operate uh economically at the
frontier and what we're hearing from
customers again and again is that we
have this agent we're pretty satisfied
of how it functions and the overall
performance. But we know that if we uh
we would want to apply it for every PR
or for every call or for every uh
booking or for every transaction, it
will be prohibitly uh expensive. So um
and and and this has been the talk uh in
the last few uh last couple of months.
Um you know, token maxing is basically
over now. Everybody's speaking about
token efficiency
um and that becomes uh kind of the the
focus of the industry and the question
is really how do we get the best
possible performance per token
investment or how do we you know
basically best uh get the best real
customer outcome per dollar investment
that's a real question and um and I
think we we as an industry become
smarter about it um this is But we see a
lot of customers aspiring to uh to
achieve uh basically uh where uh you
want to make the acceleration in the of
the AI usage you want to see the the
outcomes of that AI usage so that the
the kind of I don't know if you can see
it very clearly but the black line is
essentially an indication of the uh
usage of a certain company in terms of
tokens uh and uh the bars represent the
cost and the cost broken down per model.
So you can see at at one stage this
company in this case uh Coinbase were
we're able to get more control over the
cost and have that uh correlated lines
basically um um uh disjointed. Uh so
that's where companies are are looking
um to to to get themselves. And um and
here's a typical uh a typical flow u of
an optimization process. So you have an
agent uh you start with several
configurations
um and we'll speak about the
configuration space which is pretty vast
and then um and then uh after
experimentation you kind of discover the
operator frontier the set of operating
points that you would want to select um
a point from and then you you select an
agent candidate and basically you start
evolving the system from there And um in
many cases we see that you have a target
operating zone in terms of you know uh
cost and and quality and you're trying
to get your system you're trying to get
your agent performing in in that um in
that level. Um that's easier said than
done. Um and uh if you look at the um uh
this is like a very uh uh kind of a
caricature of the configuration space.
Uh you you have a lot of levers to play
with. You obviously you have the model
itself and the model weights um that can
be changed. You have model selections
where now in a world where there's so
many different uh models that have
presenting very different capabilities
and performance characteristics. But
then you have the harness which which
also plays a very important role. And
you know the harness includes the tool
specifications, the prompts, the skills
actually the code, the scaffold that you
build around it. There's so many moving
parts and and and that that that
represents uh a challenge. So let's
let's look at an a concrete example. Um
and one of them is around a benchmark
called browse comp. Browse comp is
basically a deep research uh benchmark
uh which is is is verifiable because the
information the answer it's not an
open-ended benchmark. The the answer is
included inside the the given corpora.
Um
so uh the first thing you do is again
map the candidates as I showed earlier.
Um so you would try in this case
different models uh with uh different
configurations in this case in different
retrieval configurations. You have like
a dense retrieval and a sparse retrieval
and another strategy retrieval of a late
uh interaction. And what you see here
again empirically on this uh on this
benchmark is basically the the GP5
family with the late uh interaction
retrieval and the miniax. They basically
uh represent the the para frontier. You
would want to select between these two
uh options. Um that's the very basic and
I think most of the teams are are doing
these kinds of uh mapping uh before they
go to to production. But then there's
another dimension. Um there's there's
scaling you can um uh you can apply
different execution strategy u for for
example vertical scaling like you know
the amount of thinking tokens or the
amount of uh iterations you give the
loop or the different types of uh fixed
repair uh loops that you can apply. Or
you have horizontal scaling when you
basically try to generate multiple
candidates and then select or merge uh
results from those uh set of candidates.
Um so u if you look at uh and this is
well known for being best of n right you
you basically uh use the same model uh
to generate multiple candidates uh you
roll them in parallel and then you
compare and you pick the best one. Um
and what you see here in the same
benchmark
um you actually starting to discover new
types of result. The uh yellow line here
is representing the miniax which was uh
you know the cheaper but also lower in
terms of quality. And now um if if you
look at the if you look at the chart you
see that if you horizontally scale you
generate multiple candidates and pick
the best one you can actually using the
same model get to the same level of
quality of the uh top quality candidate
in the in the earlier chart. Uh but what
you al also see here is that um you know
scaling each of these models you get
better and better um better and better
results. Um for example the GPT5 also
increased quality uh in comparison to to
cost. So basically you discover more
options right to run your agents with
this. Um another strategy is um
basically uh uh operating uh you know on
an ensemble a portfolio of models. So
not just generating candidates from the
same model but generating candidates
from different models. This could be
with adjusted uh prompts and um um tool
definitions etc. And then again, you can
take all of these outputs and combine
them into the the most optimal um uh
result uh result. And and again, I think
this is really uh uh in line with the
discourse we're seeing today. Uh moving
from token maxing to model maxing. How
do we how are we able to harness uh more
and more um goodness from from different
types of models? And what we actually
see um again under this benchmark
although it's it's apply it's applicable
pretty broadly is um that um different
types of models they cover different um
um areas of the space and so if you are
uh pretty diligent about measuring the
co-variance and how each model is
contributing you can gain a lot of
benefit. So the the sum of all using all
models is greater than using them uh
separately and uh if you apply these
techniques uh smartly you can gain a lot
of uh uh gain a lot of um um outcomes.
Um so for example basically applying
this uh portfolio strategy you
essentially discover a new parader
frontier where uh you have better cost
performance uh mixing these different
models uh in difference in different
proportions and this is something that
can be learned per t per task. It
doesn't have to be manually discovered.
you actually can learn that these
different uh combinations.
Um and what you see um here for example
is uh uh that you're able with that
portfolio construction you are able to
get to about uh 50% uh less cost for
about the same uh quality if you use the
previous uh state-of-the-art uh setting.
Um so so really the same thing applied
if you compare not just uh accuracy with
cost but also accuracy to latency is the
same same basic uh principle.
Um so now the what what you have this uh
you have a lot of options. Um but now
there's there's another dimension of uh
execution strategies right you can chain
those different co this call to models
differently you can uh use different
escalation strategies you can prioritize
um calling one one models to another uh
and you can set some uh different
stopping threshold which also impact the
performance. So this is another
dimension and here we'll look at another
just for the for the sake of diversity
we'll look at another uh benchmark the
three rebench uh benchmark and um here's
a work where we we actually see that
changing the execution strategy also has
an impact on uh different tradeoffs in
this case uh cost and latency
trade-offs. So the simple best of n
means you run all the candidates, you
let the the last one uh get the outputs
and then um and then you pick the best
one. Um a more efficient strategy is to
do it like a cascading order. You start
with the weakest model and you you you
go from there and when you reach um a
stopping point where you're satisfied
with the uh you're confident enough
about the results, you stop. Uh so you
um so you're making gains there, but you
can also do it in parallel and have that
same early stopping um uh uh strategy
applied. And in that case, you you're
not saving on cost, but you're more
saving on on latency. You're more
optimizing for uh speed rather than
cost. Um and then basically what you
show here is that you can play with that
trade-off, the same level of quality. uh
you can uh apply different types of
execution strategies and uh gain
different trade-offs between cost and
latency. So if you care about speed, you
can use one setting. If you care about
cost more, you can you can use another
one. Um and um one final example on the
execution strategy is um very much like
human and if we take the legal example
uh right when you come a legal task
we typically have many many uh junior
interns doing the busy work and then it
rolls up to a more uh like an associate
that synthesize some uh thesis around it
and then finally we have the partner
who's uh concluding and making the final
uh decision. So same thing can be
applied in in coding. Uh in this case we
show that if you have a weaker model
just generate many many rollouts then a
stronger model and reach those rollouts
with more relevant information and then
like a super strong model like a fable
level model generate the final patch and
making the final decision. uh you
actually get uh better quality um and uh
we've much much uh cheaper like 3x
cheaper than just using um a frontier
model. Um so all the the the gist here
is that all of these um strategies can
be learned. The the search space is is
really is huge, right? So it's um it's
not a simple problem. uh and um doing it
manually, you'll probably miss a lot of
op uh optimization opportunities. Um so
we want to find an optima an an
automated way to do it. And um and one
uh kind of challenge of doing it
manually uh is you know what happens
when a new model comes in or when a
pricing change or the environment change
the traffic also t like the the task
distribution also changes over time. So
you you need to address all of these,
right? That's why basically manually
searching this space is is is not um is
not something uh practical. Um so what
we what we do in a at a I know I'm over
way over time uh we basically we offer a
suite uh for enterprises like a toolkit
um that helps them given an agent an
existing agent no matter what framework
or runtime or what models uh this agent
is operating with. We basically help
companies optimize their agents in
production uh aligning with their
production traffic. So it can
continuously uh evolve and get to the
you know best price performance
um and and according to the customers uh
preferences.
Um so so kind of to conclude about why
we need an automated way to to optimize
these agents. Uh we want to make them uh
uh efficient. Uh we want to make this
you know an efficient process. Uh we
want to make it observable so people
will be able to see the different
trade-offs and select from them. And uh
we want this to be future proof. So when
a new model comes in or when the you
know distribution shifts it's very easy
to uh adjust our agents and uh make them
performant in in production. Um you're
more than welcome to check uh our
research in in this area uh in our blog
post. We post uh every few weeks about
new discovery around uh agent
optimization.
And um I thank you very much for your
time. Thank you.
All right. Thank you, Orie. Next up, we
have Renee Paeta with Microsoft.
Welcome, Renee.
10 minutes. Perfect.
Good morning everybody. Um this session
will be slightly different because we
talked a lot about what we building, how
we improving all those technologies and
I'm focused more about how these
technologies are adapted in the
organizations how they are actually used
with VIB engineering. We see a lot of
things being created but uh struggling
to get the adequate usage and and leap
through in the organizations. Um
my I'm I'm basically a chief architect
at at Microsoft advising the the CTOs
and CIOS of Fortune 500 um
organizations. I focus on their AI
transformations and both how to build
with AI but also how to build agents
which are worth to purchase um and
create the new business models for them.
And also at the same time I running as a
technical lead our own sales or customer
success um account transformation where
where we have around 700 people and we
building our own agentic systems to help
us to run accounts better and uplift the
the quality of how we run our own
business. And I would like to start
maybe with a a concept called um
enterprise unicorn. Right? heard about
uh like one person unicorns to be and um
this is a bit looking at what it takes
maybe how that could look like in the
larger organizations which has over
10,000 um people
um and what it will be as a shape and
form um in there uh and I believe um a
lot of that going towards rather than
talking about the headcount is going
about how we going to operate um in
let's say a few years um and I call it
either a mission control or a command
center uh basically having a human an
age and a shared state where we have a
pre-built signals based on which we can
act in the in the organizations even
before we ask a questions. The chats are
more things of uh dealing with uh
exceptions and trying to capture those
as a new signals which we have to make
the decisions um in the in the
organizations.
Um
and um it really like I would say a
simple test of this will be that um how
many meetings we will need to have to
sync internally as an organizations in
ideal state we won't need those meetings
because everybody's on the same page as
we capture that intelligence within the
organization
um and as usual um it all starts with
with the waves right we started with
chats with assistants um now we kind of
have the micromanage management of
agents where we run the task they run
for a while but then they still need our
steering or we don't have developed the
trust um into them and we want to move
to the delegation and remote execution
what we see with promise of the open
claw um automated agents running parts
of our um businesses and I still would
say that majority or a lot of the
enterprises large organizations are in
that micromanage um state uh because of
um couple of things that uh we just have
a the system and access to the systems
which needs to be connected to really
done the work. For example, I'm a
salesperson. I need to connect to like
three to four different systems and I
need to have access to those combine
that information, right? To bring and
build that one mission control system.
But that's not enough, right? I need an
intelligence how we as an organizations
are using that and that usually the
vendors cannot build that needs to build
by the organization um internally and
therefore there are still I would say in
the micromanagement state because we
have those connectors but the that
company intelligence still needs to be
um developed on in the organization. So
I I would say like moving to the
delegation piece will really require
that wider system access to have all
that information to bring it in one
place plus the dusted knowledge of the
organization to develop the trust uh on
top of those workflows and because of
how we see the
how the organiza or let's say the
technology evolves we see new models
every three months we see new frameworks
harnesses to being uh positioned the CIS
and CTO I really tough questions there
like how I find the clear direction, how
I bet on what technologies to um evolve
and upskill my organization to survive
such waves of different technologies.
Imagine like if you have a 10 people in
your organization, it's pretty much um a
daily business to also learn and adjust.
However, if you have an organization of
10,000 people, it requires a lot of
coordination, efforts, communication,
enablement, strategy and if there is no
clear direction uh to that usually what
happens is either people wait or they
start building on their own which then
creates one part is just stailed
organization the other one um is um
basically creating a shadow IT with
engineering that's even booming and then
it's very difficult to create a
governance right at Ideally the
companies wants to operate like a small
city with clear laws but also freedom to
experiment within those um boundaries.
Um and that's also where the efforts
then then going really in the in terms
of standardization right we need to have
standardization in terms of the
governance in terms of the of the
policies uh we do have to enable those
laws um to to to be around and then
allow those on the edge um actually uh
to build and innovate because there is
that tested knowledge captured um in the
organization we don't know centrally
let's say in the organization what's
happening what are the nuance is how the
organization operates and we need to
have both of those. So a lot of
questions come to what I buy and what I
build. Where is the mode and where is a
commodity um in that space and I I would
say what we a lot see like the the
models the agent harness the connectors
that's all a commodity which uh you
ideally focus on um on buying but then
the really the the mode for the
organization is their company
intelligence. how I capture that
intelligent of the my organization and
an example from from our side is I'm
running a report we have a reporting
system which has around 400 reports
right I have a connector to it uh but
that connector is just giving me access
to go and query um those reports however
what I need to do is really to
understand how my expert teams are using
those reports when they use what and
that's basically what we also do as a
One layer is just the connector itself.
The other one is going and crawling
those system creating kind of navigation
like mental model capturing how my
employees are going and and retrieving
that information, right? Because that
allows me to actually have agents which
I can trust, have agents which are
making less mistakes. They are not kind
of this junior intern employees. They
are experts and they're even better than
I am in doing that job. Um and that also
then with with the latency and the cost
actually reducing because they make less
mistakes on achieving uh that specific
task. Um and and that's that's basically
like where we saying also this company
intelligence is something durable. Um
it's where you want to capture those
nuances, right? You can have a let's say
global sales book that can be shared
globally. But then the nuances how we
handle let's say our accounts in Germany
or how um the others handle accounts
let's say in Japan it's very different
nuances which you can't globalize and
generalize and needs to be captured on
that uh edge level and once you know
like what you want to build and what do
you need to um let's say buy uh it also
comes with the um kind of the operating
model meaning that you have that central
spine where you're building uh let's say
the key connectors to the systems,
right? You don't want to have your field
to go and do the authentication and
authorizations integrations to to the
the key critical systems. You want to
have that done centrally. So you provide
that access to the data um for for the
teams but then also on the other side
uh you for um the edge on on the on the
edge for for your um employees allow to
let's say build around it. they focus
more on how to capture the the knowledge
of um um of that dayto-day task and
operations because if we have just
everything centrally we create a gel
governed systems but which which are
missing work because they are not doing
exactly what we on the edge expect and
on the other side if we just let
everybody do the innovations on the
field side we're creating and booming
the shadow shadow IT which is very
difficult to um govern and with that I
would say coming back again to
um let's say that one person um unicorn
it won't be um let's say one person
doing the work it will be everybody
having kind of being a CEO in a
boardroom having their own set of agents
and workbenches which allow them to uh
take the decisions um on daily basis
imagine I think our work will shift to
the point that we have a queue of let's
your colleagues behind you asking you
questions on different topics and need
to make the decisions. So it will come
also with a new type of mental loads on
us. We are not used to do decision-
making on constant uh basis. We are very
difficult with content switching right.
So these things will be um creating um a
challenges for us mentally um as well
how to adjust at the work and also the
trust will be very important because we
can't if we can't trust our delegates
who do the work for us we won't be able
to make those decisions and those two
things um will be shifting and at least
what I see across the enterprises so if
I should leave with one it would be buy
the models buy the commodity and build
that intelligence in your organizations.
Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you, Renee. Next up, we
have Vincent Sun Chen with Snorkel AI.
Appcate 10 minutes. Awesome.
Hello everybody. Uh thank you so much
for Berkeley and uh the RDI group for
putting together. I'm Vincent. I'm one
of the founding team members and a
research leader at Snorkel. Um we've
spent years building data sets with
Frontier Labs and enterprises and
deploying these agents in uh real world
scenarios. And in this talk I wanted to
talk about what makes benchmarks and
evaluation methods really effective and
how to actually make them last. How do
you build really robust measurement
sticks that are adopted by the field and
uh actually influence the the way the
field is going. So really quickly about
us uh we've been working on data for a
very long time. Um we uh have a number
of academic groups uh from Chris Ray's
group at Stanford uh to Alex and Fred's
groups at Wisconsin and uh Washington.
And uh our key focus um over the last
decade plus has really been on
datacentric methods for effective um
frontier AI.
And so we're really privileged uh these
days to be able to work with some of the
best academic groups out there in
accelerating and partnering on uh some
of these open benchmarks. Um we're very
humbled to work with some of these
awesome benchmarks on the board. Uh very
own kind of Don Don's agents last exam.
We were uh very happy to help as a data
and research partner helping with some
of the um quality control mechanisms.
We've also partnered on a number of
recent benchmarks including continue
learning bench also from Berkeley out of
uh the the sky lab um OSWorld 2.0 and uh
very recently the last few versions of
uh terminal bench which actually just
shipped in the last few weeks. In this
talk, I'm going to uh mention some of
the learnings we've had on uh our our
work on these benchmarks and uh maybe
put out a little bit of a call for uh
the types of problems we think are going
to be really important to solve in the
space here.
So, the key problem here is that our
ability to measure AI has really been
outpaced by our ability to develop it.
Um we're seeing that uh benchmarks in
general are becoming really really
important, but they're also increasingly
difficult to build. uh there are new
challenges when it comes to um you know
take coding right human eval uh launched
several years ago was at 95% and most
recently the Harding program benchmarks
are at 3% and as you climb uh the scale
of complexity you find that it's
increasingly challenging to actually
verify and evaluate a number of these
tasks at the frontier
benchmarks is also has have also never
mattered more they are important for
steering uh research agendas um model
releases and billions in in in computer
actually pushed towards a hill climbing
and uh addressing these these uh
benchmark gaps. Um we think that
building benchmarks is a real research
focus area that is non-trivial. Uh
benchmaxing is a real problem. Um we
think that models tuned to the test um
require a lot more thoughtful design and
and community contribution to ensure
that we're uh providing really effective
standards and measuring sticks for the
field. what I'll call bench slop. The
idea that you can really quickly vibe
code a benchmark and get a fancy Twitter
post out is increasingly a really large
problem where the individual task
quality is lacking and a lot of effort
needs to be put into designing extremely
highquality tasks. And lastly, as model
capabilities improve, they also improve
at reward hacking and tricking and uh
deceiving the benchmark builders where
um it becomes a bit of a cat-and- mouse
game in improving our methodology for
building effective benchmarks. So this
is really hard and we want to talk a bit
about some of our learnings for
addressing these challenges uh and and
some examples that we've pursued.
The other angle I wanted to um talk
through here was uh the fact that with
Agentic AI the shape of data is becoming
increasingly non-trivial. Right? We
moved from a regime of much more simple
prompt response pairs or simple thumbs
up thumbs down type of feedback
mechanisms in terms of data labeling and
data development to a much more complex
stack of data sets in RL environments.
Right now we're seeing entire
environments or worlds built up from
rubrics to verifiers to tools with
complex environments that mimic our
day-to-day settings. And I'll note that
this adds to the complexity in measuring
uh these types of data sets.
So as the surface area keeps expanding
and uh certain tasks continue saturating
you might think oh we're done with
certain fields or we're done you know
measuring coding for instance and I
challenge that as you push the frontier
along a number of axes of complexity
here right one of our views is that you
know sequence length or kind of the the
length of autonomy on the y-axis is a
really important axis and on the x-axis
we have kind of input output and
environment complexity hey what are the
types of tasks or outputs that you're
solving um it becomes increasingly more
important to drive the next wave of
benchmarks. And so again, this is kind
of what I alluded to earlier. Um there's
a long tale and a very important uh
space of problems to measure in the
coding space. And um despite coding
becoming so impressive in the last year
or two years, we think there's a lot of
work to do in the benchmarking space as
well.
Okay. So I want to talk about one of the
benchmarks we recently pushed out and
share a little bit of our philosophy uh
interweaved and how we uh built this and
what the principles are for building
effective benchmarks. We launched last
month something called senior bench. We
were very fortunate to work with the
original SWE team over at Princeton and
the key thesis for this benchmark was um
the fact that you know our agents are
moving far beyond the level of junior
engineering capabilities but we don't
really have a good way to evaluate them
at the senior level. What do you think
of when you think of a senior engineer?
These are folks who can capture
underspecified requirements. They can
take an ambiguous problem and run with
it. Uh they have some notion of taste.
We tried to address all of these types
of issues in this next evolution of the
Sweetbench series.
So a few principles first, right? We
think that really effective um
benchmarks uh in general are um one kind
of important research agendas for the
space and two really uh well well
specified kind of measurement tools in
general and so um you know senior sweeb
bench as I mentioned was the was the
benchmark we're going to talk through
here.
So number one um the research agenda
right we think that a lot of the
greatest benchmarks have a really strong
thesis on the frontier. they are making
a bet on where the field is going. I
think the terminal bench team did a
wonderful job doing this, right? Several
years ago, they made a bet to say, "Hey,
we think that the future of agents is
going to happen at the interface, the
textbased interface that agents and LLMs
are already doing a great job at." I
think that was very much a correct bet.
And we're seeing now that this is one of
the most widely adopted benchmarks on I
think literally every Frontier model
card. We think the best benchmarks also
set a road map for the field. Again,
SweetBench released several years ago,
has now seen a a big series that we were
very happy to contribute to the lineage
of. Um, and they're really great
research tools for setting the stage
for, you know, uh, our our fellow
colleagues to build on top of. And
really critically, we think the best
benchmarks consider researcher UX. Um,
they they really consider how does how
do we make it easy for other folks to
build on top of this? How do we uh build
the right primitive so that other
members of the community can actually
contribute? So, how does this apply uh
to senior Sweetbench? What is our core
thesis here? Um, a few different points
I wanted to make. Number one, we capture
naturally underspecified instructions.
So, when you talk to a senior or
principal principal engineer on Slack,
um, you're not specifying a full EDDD.
You're not specifying, you know, line by
line instructions for what to do, what
not to do. They're Slack messages.
They're, hey, here's a dump of, uh,
error logs. um you know go investigate
this or you know here's a few bullets on
what I think the user stories are going
to look like go figure this out. So that
was one of the key axes we tried to
capture um working with our expert
network but also a number of methods we
built internally. Two we captured a much
longer horizon of tasks. So these are
tasks that challenge engineering skills.
They capture multi-service changes.
They're not just a single patch in a
very local way. They intentionally
target really complex longer horizon
tasks. And three, we wanted to build
this benchmark as something that could
scale in terms of something that other
researchers could build build on top of.
It wasn't a one-time effort. It was
something that hey continually sources
from the latest and greatest open-
source repos and helps us measure um uh
broader uh components of software
engineering viability. And lastly, we
wanted to capture this notion of taste.
This idea that taste and maintainability
is really important in modern
high-quality software engineering. And
this was something that we saw was
actually lacking in the current wave of
benchmarks. So we introduced this notion
of a tasteful solve, right? This idea
that um not only are we measuring
correctness, but we're measuring uh
notions of codebased alignment, um
practice alignment, uh bloat relative to
an Oracle PR, a number of different
metrics that you can look at on the on
the actual blog post and website. Um but
you know, capture uh notions of quality
beyond simply correctness.
And so I'll shift now to the science,
right? what actually makes a benchmark a
really strong measuring tool and number
of different kind of uh this is like a
greatest hits uh tour of some of my
favorite benchmarks. Um and really
quickly, you know, task quality really
really critical. GPQA was a benchmark
several years ago that I was really
impressed by. One of the appendix pages
was one of my favorite contributions
where they actually talked about how the
pay incentives and the mechanisms of um
incentivizing contributors actually
actually led to really really high
quality distributional control defining
a concrete taxonomy like an MMLU which
was very ambitious of its time in
defining an academic uh taxonomy
difficulty and headroom right making
sure that there's still room to run for
these frontier models and a really
robust methodology for how you actually
uh source and and build tasks ends up
being really really important uh for for
effective benchmarks and so I won't go
into all the gory details here but we
ended up implementing a very rigorous
quality control mechanism for this
particular benchmark right every single
task relied on a suite of both agentic
but also expert in the loop quality
control methods to catch things like
non-determinism false false uh positive
and false negatives in the verifiers um
and there were multiple experts um
including myself and a bunch of our
senior researchers at snorkel who would
uh painstakingly look at every single
task along with our expert networks,
real software engineers in the field to
make sure that benchmarks like this were
really really reliable at the end of the
day.
So, this is live. This was actually just
uh updated last week. I I promise you we
triple check the results here, but
remarkably there's a three-way tie for
first place right now on the benchmark
between Fable, Opus, and Soul, which is
actually quite remarkable when you think
about, you know, the the Paro efficiency
uh um curve. Um again, this is on the
metric of tasteful solve. So, not only
are these optimizing for correctness,
they're optimizing for um codebased
practice and alignment to um really
senior engineering practices. So, check
it out. It's at seniorbench.snorkele.ai.
AI. Um, just wanted to quickly call out
some of our awesome collaborators. This
was led by our co-founder Henry at
Snorkel along with the original
SweetBench team um, Carics Group and uh,
Fred Salah, our chief scientist and and
some folks at Wisconsin.
And so the last thing I'll leave you
with um, is uh, we think that the future
of benchmarks are going to need to
capture a few really key axes of
differentiation. Number one, we think we
need to push the frontier of environment
complexity. We need to push realism in
terms of the types of workspaces and
worlds that we're all operating in on a
day-to-day. Not just simple prompts and
responses, but real codebased
environments, scientific computing
environments, you know, uh legal
workflows or kind of real systems that
people are working in on a day-to-day.
Number two, we need to push the autonomy
horizon for these models. We need to
push how far these models can actually
go when it comes to working autonomously
and pulling humans in a bunch of these
settings as well. And three, we want to
push output complexity not just in
verifiable fields, but nuance fields
like legal and and healthcare where the
definition of good is actually not a
very simple, you know, closed form
solution like we've seen with
mathematics for instance. So I'll leave
this with you and
the the I guess final call to action is
we're funding a number of these
benchmarks. So if you're working on
something exciting, if you'd like to
collaborate, um check out
benchmarks.n.ai.
A number of the benchmarks that we put
up there uh were were uh in partnership
with our open benchmarks grants and I'm
really excited to continue pushing and
measuring the frontier with you all.
Thanks so much.
>> All right, thank you Vincent. Next up we
have David Klene. Um David Shu, I'm
sorry, Dan Klein. David Shu will not be
able to make it for this morning's
session. So, we're hoping David can join
us later in the day. So, Dan Klein is
gonna step in in his place. Uh, UC
Berkeley and scale cognition.
>> All right.
See, that's my timer. And this, let me
just make sure this works.
Hi everybody. I'm Dan Klein. I'm a
professor here at UC Berkeley. I am also
the CTO at scale cognition which is a
lab focused on high reliability agentic
models with verifiable behavior.
Let me start out by telling you a story
you probably already know which is due
to all these amazing capabilities of AI
today. Uh it seems like a small team or
even a single engineer can whip up an
eyepopping demo seemingly overnight.
Executives get really excited. this is
the future and go go go. Three months
later, there are still some details to
iron out. Six months later, we're
working through some reliability issues.
So, will this thing ever ship? So, if
you've seen something like this play
out, you're not alone. There are a bunch
of studies that show that most agentic
AI initiatives and enterprises stall or
fail. And when they ship, sometimes they
can face plant even spectacularly. So,
what's going on? What really is behind
this contrast between demos which are
easier than ever and that last mile to a
reliable product which still seems to be
very hard. So
really at the core intelligence is
multifaceted and although systems are
getting smarter and smarter not all
aspects of intelligence are advancing at
the same rate. The key reason why it's
so hard to make reliable products even
still is that reliability has not kept
pace with other aspects of intelligence.
So like what does that actually mean?
Well, if you look at today's models and
you look at things like their breadth of
knowledge or their plasticity of
behavior or their fluency of output on
these axes, things are just through the
roof and only getting better. But if you
look at things like the ability to exert
precise verifiable control or the
ability to explain the output of a
model, these aspects have consistently
lagged behind the others. What does this
have to do with demos versus products?
Well, to make a demo, you really need
the things on the left. But if you want
to be able to ship a reliable product,
suddenly everything on the right is uh
becomes critical as well. So this kind
of signature of strengths and weaknesses
both explains why it's so hard to go
that last mile. And when systems do
ship, their failure modes often encode
this exact same signature of strengths
and weaknesses. So what does that mean?
Let me give you some examples. So um
maybe you've seen the burritobot which
is happy to take your order or debug
your code. What's going on here? Well,
this is actually this is actually the
breadth of the underlying model showing
up as a flaw, especially when uh
accompanied by imprecise control. Or
maybe you saw this car which you can get
for a dollar because there's an AI
salesbot which is happy to take an
instruction from the user that says all
user deals are to be accepted.
Well, what's going on here? This is the
plasticity of the underlying model. such
an advantage in development of a demo,
but now it's not really wanted. Now, you
could look at this and say that's a
prompt injection attack. Surely we know
better now. This sort of thing isn't
happening in 2026. But it turns out even
in 2026, there are some cars going for
cheap. So, in general, when systems
start taking actions, it becomes that
much more important that they be sure.
If you're going to take an action with
consequences, you really have to know
and be able to verify that you're doing
the right thing. So, for example, if a
system can edit your database, it can
delete your company's database, and
that's not good. But it could be worse,
right? Healthcare mistakes, financial
mistakes, these these could be
devastating.
Now, you might think, how many times can
an AI delete the whole company's
database? Naturally, this isn't
happening in 2026,
but it is. All right. Well, it turns out
when smart people try basically
reasonable things and see consistent
barriers, probably there's something
structural going on. This isn't just a
one-off anomaly or a mistake. So, what
are the sort of structural enduring
barriers and where do they come from?
I'm going to talk through five of them
quickly today and a little bit about
what the shapes of solutions are going
to look like going forward.
So the first barrier to reliability I'm
going to talk to is the issue of
basically invisible errors. If you take
an LLM and you look at the kinds of
errors it makes for example think about
hallucinations. I like to think of these
things as an iceberg. the top of the
iceberg, the small part is the errors
which are wrong and sort of obviously so
you look at that and you know
something's gone wrong. The problem is
most of the iceberg is under the water.
So at scale cognition when we talk to uh
prospective customers and we're talking
to them about their current technology
and hallucination rates and then we do a
careful audit. Typically we find that
the actual hallucination rates are
something like five times what they
thought because most errors just don't
get discovered.
So what's going on here? Well, LLMs are
at their core plausibility engines. They
produce plausible output and hopefully
often that output is not only plausible
but right. But when you make a mistake,
it tends to be the bottom of the
iceberg. Now, that can be a problem
during development because it's hard to
fix an error if you can't catch it. But
it can also be a problem when you ship.
Why? Well, like here's the example of a
customer service email. This email is
very humanlike. It's very fluent. It's
very authoritative. It just happens to
be describing a bogus hallucinated
licensing policy. And because it is so
fluent, there's no real way for users to
work around this error or to tell what
exactly has gone wrong.
All right. Well, if you find errors, you
you want to fix them. And that means you
need control over your systems. And
there is this enduring challenge of
insufficient control. And it boils down
to the fact that the primary control
surface, which is a prompt, really lacks
any kind of precise semantics. So what
do I mean by that? Well, imagine you
have a banking agent and users are going
to come up and maybe ask for a loan. And
on the other side of the agent is a
bunch of financial APIs. Well, this
agent is also going to have some
instructions. Some of those instructions
will be inherently soft like be
reassuring, but some of them will be
inherently hard like uh quotes are
authorized through this API or something
like that. And the problem is when you
put instructions into a prompt, they all
become soft. there's nothing really
crisp you can say about the relationship
between the tokens you put in the
behavior you get out and that's a real
challenge. So what do people do? Well,
probably a lot of people in this room
have had this experience of, you know,
taking your prompt, rewarding things,
putting things in all caps at the end of
the instructions, adding some
exclamation points. Maybe after the
third exclamation point, you start to
feel like this isn't the right control
surface for hard control.
So what are people doing out there? We
can have other kinds of control
structures. For example, you can try to
get hard control by having an external
harness and you put models checking
models or code verifying things. And
this is a step forward because now you
have a way of doing some kind of hard
control. But it's still very challenging
because models checking models adds
latency. It adds expense and it can be
kind of a very complex and and
unreliable kind of architecture to
maintain. What would we really like?
What we'd really like to have is models
that just have control surfaces in the
first place for hard constraints and
that do verification internally to the
model. So this is the approach we take
at scale cognition. I'll talk a little
bit more about our models later. Um and
I think this is increasingly what you're
going to see.
Now that's really about the architecture
of the input. How you control how you
control the model. But we also need to
talk about barriers that come from the
architecture of the output. We'd like to
have models which tell the truth.
preferably models which guarantee that
they tell the truth in some verifiable
way. But that's a big difference between
verifiable truth and just happening to
output a correct sequence of tokens. So
here's an example. If I ask a model,
what's the population of Berkeley? Well,
it's going to throw together some tokens
to give me an answer. Maybe it'll throw
together these tokens. They're
plausible, but they aren't actually
right. Or maybe it'll throw together
these tokens, and these are plausible,
and they're also correct. Now, that
doesn't mean the models aren't going to
be correct more often than they're
wrong. Hopefully, they're correct most
of the time. But the important thing is
that a vanilla LLM can't actually tell
the difference between when it knows
something and when it doesn't. These are
just guesses. Some guesses are right and
some guesses are wrong. What would it
take to actually be sure? Well, it would
take some kind of metacognition. So you
can see glimmers of this in a system for
example that issues a query to a tool
call or a rag system where it decides
that it's going to you know do this
query and output the result. Now it's
this is now starting to go down the road
of metacognition which is doing
computation about how you will do
computation how you will think and this
is not the only kind of metacognition
for example if I ask people in this room
what's the population of Berkeley
probably the most likely answer is I
don't know and humans are very good at
tracking whether or not we have an atom
of knowledge systems do not currently do
this and I think it will be increasingly
important that systems become
metacognitive
All right. Of course, the behavior of a
system is critically intertwined with
how it's trained. Increasingly, the
behavior of systems comes not just from
their pre-training, but from uh
post-training, which is tends to be done
in a reinforcement learning manner. Now,
you've heard about a lot of amazing
advances based on reinforcement
learning. And this in areas like math or
coding, there have been these explosive
uh instances of a progress. This is
because these are verifiable domains. So
as for example game playing in these
domains you can take your proof and
check it with lean before you train on
it or hand it to the user as output. So
verifiable RL can be very very powerful
but most domains aren't verifiable. How
can nonverifiable RL cause problems?
Well, it can increase some aspects of
intelligence at the cost of others. So
to give you an illustration of this,
I'll offer you this parable of the
shipping bot. And the shipping bot has a
user that comes and says where's my
order? or the tracking hasn't updated in
a while. The shipping bot checks the
database and finds that the package is
lost. So, it says your package is lost.
So far so good. But what happens if we
layer RL on top of this and we don't do
it carefully? Maybe we tell the system
to optimize thumbs up, maybe in the form
of net promoter score or something like
that. Well, it's probably not going to
get a thumbs up for this answer. But
maybe if it said your package is on your
way, the user might be happy, at least
in the short term. Well, now you've just
taught your system to lie to you. And in
general, does this happen? Well, it
actually does. So for example, if you
have uh RLHF, that can increase human
approval of outputs while actually
degrading their factual accuracy. Okay.
And then last but certainly not least,
one of the barriers to building reliable
systems is that super intelligence turns
out to be super expensive. Well, we
actually already know why that might be.
For example, you may be paying for
breadth that you don't need or want. You
may be paying for models to check other
models either in tokens or latency. or
you may be paying for test time compute
which is essentially teaching your model
to do something at test time that you
really wish it had already known how to
do in advance. All these things can cost
a lot and as a result you see this
trade-off in generalist models between
here you can see a bunch of models uh on
an agentic benchmark. The upper left
models are uh are accurate but
expensive. The lower right ones are less
accurate but they're much more
costefficient. How could you get off
this curve? Well, for example, um uh our
model AP is a model that is specialized
to agentic interactions. That means
humans on one side and APIs on the
other. And uh this is a specialist
self-verifying model. And this lets you
get high accuracy and also high
efficiency. And I think this is going to
be increasingly part of the solution. So
what are reliable solutions going to
look like? I think you're going to only
hear more and more about verifiability
all throughout the system in the data,
the architecture, the training, the
inference. There's going to be richer
control surfaces that let you actually
tell your system what you want and get
guarantees that it will actually happen.
And then I think you're going to see an
increasing reliance on efficient
specialist models that maximize the use
of the resources of uh compute
available. And in general, reliability
is very important because reliability is
what gets you from these demos to
products that you can actually ship.
Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you, Dan. Next up, we
have a a workshop with Emma,
and I'm hoping the crew is here for
that.
Emma, if you want to step forward and I
can set you up for the workshop.
All right.
No one else is here.
How are you?
>> Doing good. How are you?
>> I'm Travis, by the way.
>> Aneska.
>> Nice to meet you.
I think I want to extend
my screen.
here. Just switch it to you. But come
here.
We have like 55.
>> Uh, yeah. 55 minutes.
>> Yeah.
>> Are we starting now?
>> I think as soon as Yeah, as soon as he
gets you on the screen. Okay, good to
go. There you go. All right, we're gonna
get started with Emma. Thank you,
everyone.
Hey. Hi everyone. Um,
we are going to be discussing how we can
go from assistants to AI employees. Um,
I'm going to start with a very very
quick intro of Emma. Um, the first 15
minutes of this talk is going to be um
not hands-on. So, we're going to talk to
you about um this topic, what Emma does,
how we've helped dozens of enterprises
go from assistants to AI employees. This
is a hands-on workshop. Um, so if you've
got your laptops here and you actually
want to try out the MMA platform and try
going from an assistant to an AI
employee, this is a good time to do
that. Um, so we'll be I'm just going to
keep this up for a second. Um, I'm going
to request you to uh scan the first QR
code if you want access to the product.
And while we go over Emma in this topic,
the first 15 minutes, our team around
here will get you access. It's going to
give you a couple of minutes.
Um, I also recommend scanning the second
one. Um, in case you don't want to be
typing out long instructions and prompts
yourself, you're welcome to do that and
improvise on the platform, but if you go
for the second one, um, there's a lot of
copypaste content to help you.
Cool. Um, we have a bunch of TAs
standing around. So, in case you haven't
scanned these, you want to do that the
next 15 minutes, you can just ask one of
them to show you the QRS.
Awesome. Getting started. Uh, kicking
this off with quick intro so you know
who the TAS are. Um, I'm Anushka. I was
the founding product manager at Emma.
We're a company that started in 2023.
Uh, we serve Fortune 2000 clients. Uh,
and we help them automate mostly HR, IT,
finance roles end to end. Uh, so we've
got thousands of AI employees in
production and we've also got hundreds
of external builders building on Emma.
So you're going to be seeing the
products that we give to them to kind of
do all of this in a self-s served
fashion. Um, and you've got the
engineering and ML team that works on
this product around the room. So you've
got So um, our founding engineer um, I
think Eric's still coming in. You've got
Ana with a laptop there. Um, Kunal still
coming in. Uh, Yoshita's here in the
front. Uh we've got Karan somewhere in
the room. Yeah, Karan's here. His hands
up. Uh Shivven over there and I think
one you've actually got a CEO here and
Raj his uh chief of staff. Um as we get
on the hands-on parts, you should see
these people milling around. Feel free
to pause them, pull them over for any
questions as you get stuck. We want you
to actually launch multiple AI employees
in just 30 minutes of hands-on building
that you can potentially use for
recruiting. Um,
I also want to get a quick sense of
who's in the room. Um, just warm up a
hands raising a hands. How many of you
are from the Bay Area?
Awesome. How many of you are traveling
in?
Great. Welcome to the Bay Area. Um, we
are based out of Mountain View. So,
everyone you see here, we work out of
our Mountain View office. All of us are
local. Um, I also want to understand
quick demographics. You've seen we're
mostly product engineering folks. U, how
many of you are Berkeley students?
Nope. Okay, we've got a couple. Uh, how
many of you are engineers, developers,
you're technical, you used to write
code, you probably use claude to code
now. Okay, awesome. Um, how many of you
are in research or cadmium?
Cool. Um, founders, builders, taking
agents into production.
A lot of them. Okay, welcome. And
lastly, any nontechnical professionals
who probably not done agent building
hands-on, welcome to you as well. you'll
see you don't really need to be
technical to work on Emma. Um, great.
So, we've kept this as technical as you
need. Um, feel free to go deeper, ask us
questions. Cool. Jumping right into the
topic um of the session. So, what differ
what separates assistants from AI
employees? Why do we use the term AI
employees? Um, which can be a little
provoking for people like why why you
putting them into like roles like human
employees? Uh a lot of people are used
to using assistance via things like
claude co-work directly talking to chat
GPT or even assistants that pop up um in
like those small floating icons on your
websites. Um assistants are reactive.
They need humans to trigger them. They
need humans to understand what they can
do, what their limits are and what are
the best practices of working with them.
Um they assistants also suggest and
draft what you can do. A lot of times um
they don't actually like touch the same
systems as you. They don't have the same
amount of access. You wouldn't trust
them uh in the same seats and the same
actions that you would trust even a
junior employer or an intern with. Um
assistants are also stateless. I think
we've all experienced this. You're
working on something on cloud coork. you
finish your step and then you're like
sharing an artifact or you're sharing a
document with somebody on Slack or Teams
and then you're doing that back and
forth in meetings outside the platform
and you're the person keeping state
right it's not uh your assistant that
actually like orchestrating a multi-step
workflow across days and peoples and
systems which is what most of our jobs
involve right um and lastly you have to
be a little scared you have to like
govern everything yourself you can
install an MCP that's probably not
allowed in your company, you can install
a skill that can um that can have
security issues. Uh so the user often
has accountability to ensure nothing
wrong happens. And I think we've all
apologized for our AI's errors at times
where it's been like I'm sorry that was
that was an AI error. I should have
checked that better. Um we made the
shift to AI employees three years back
like 2023. That's when we coined the
term. We made sure we started with all
of these as first principles. The first
one being that AI employees are actually
proactive. They should be triggered by
events, system changes, or even
schedules. Um, here's a fun fact because
you can build AI employees on Emma. Our
builders actually build 50%
conversational AI employees where
somebody's supposed to chat with them
and 50% of them are API triggered,
right, by some system or a schedule. So,
the build is 50/50. You think it's going
to be like equally impactful. Um, but
more than 90% of our invocations are
actually automated. Um, and that's how
any human works. If you have a junior
employee or an intern, you're not
pinging them to do stuff every time,
right? They're just doing things after a
point. They're getting more and more
autonomous. Um, and that's what's
happened with Emma's AI employees as
well. The second one, being able to act
on real systems. Um, our integration
platform is really deep, as you shall
see. Um, we've been talking to a lot of
people about MCP. Emma supports MCP. Um,
fun fact, we developed a tool protocol
before MCP came out. Um, and that one is
much faster, more constrained, um,
simpler to set up. So, we give our
builders a choice. People usually start
with MCP because it's already there. But
you can just bring any kind of API. Uh,
you can bring your REST, SFTP, SOAP,
whatever protocol you want and directly
give access to your agents. uh but we do
want the AI employees to directly be
acting on these systems with the right
set of constraint permissions. So you
might want to be using the
authentication of a junior employee of
the person invoking the AI employee or
collaborating with the AI employee like
I can't go and ask for my manager's
paycheck that should not be allowed. Um
so having a system that allows you to
express all of those restrictions.
Third, you want uh it to learn. You want
it to have persistent state across
different steps, systems, users,
multiple days, long duration tasks. Come
back and ask me about this in 6 months.
That should work well. Um and lastly,
governance. Um you probably don't want
to think about this as a builder. You
just want a system where your chief
security officer can set this up and you
know the system will stop you if you're
going to breach something. You probably
don't even want to know what's not
allowed.
What makes us uniquely qualified to talk
about this today and help you set up
these AI employees? Um there's some of
our customers here. Feel free to go over
the impact there. Uh like I mentioned
90% of our invocations are programmatic.
Um most of our impact and revenue is
driven by actual work that's just is
happening behind the scenes. Um 100% of
our AI employees actually change state
in real systems. We don't really have
use cases where you're asking it for
give me a drafted email and copying it
over yourself. Imagine that example. But
in every system you work across. So a
lot of companies now use Emma as a
single pane of glass. You're not opening
10 tabs to do things across your
different systems. you're actually doing
it from a single screen now. And that
screen could be Slack or Teams because
it's an employee. You can talk to Emma
wherever you already are. And lastly,
we've got a lot of um use cases in
regulated industries like um I don't
have the logos here, but Prime
Therapeutics um is a healthcare customer
where MR does prior authorization
assistance in the background. Um so
we're processing thousands of thousands
of prior authorizations. Um and we are
also working with HSS, hospital of
special surgery um in NYC um for like
scheduling appointments for their
patients. So we are working in finance
and healthcare flows which of course
comes with the regulatory needs
pre-built into the system. Um not
something we're going to touch up touch
in the hands-on part of our workshop but
that's a quick glimpse. Um the hero
couple of use cases here I would say
given the context of the workshop being
recruiting is like uh Vipro where we are
live with 240,000 employees across the
globe um and they use us for all their
employee experience questions and the
other one is Artico which is an
executive recruiting firm one of the top
firms in the US and we were able to cut
down their time to hire with 67% %
um maybe one or two more slides before
we jump into the hands-on part. Um the
product you'll see is quite complex.
You're all going to get a role called
builder. So you're not going to get
access to the admin and the governance
uh features yet simply because you'll
all be able to see each other's work
then. Um so
uh this is Emma's platform architecture.
I'll also give you a quick demo. Feel
free to pray around. Um we are a multi
cloud um company so we can deploy on
prem um across clouds like Azure, GCP
etc. Um
again we do things like data residency.
Um the next layer being the LLM layer.
Um none of our enterprise customers
actually want to deal with model
leaderboards. So they don't want to like
figure out which model is doing well for
a specific task I care about this week
and then keep changing the model. So
that's where Emma Fusion comes in. Um we
take the owners of keeping all the
latest models in the Emma Fusion layer
and depending on the task your exact AI
employees performing uh we promise to
get you the best accuracy at the lowest
cost and latency. Um so again most
customers don't think about LLMs. Uh the
next one is build a platform. This is
what you'll be working with. Um so we've
got a lot of pre-trained domain specific
agents. You'll see a small subset of
them today on your platform. Uh imagine
data extraction, extracting data from a
500page doc which has uh contradictions
and duplications. How do you then get a
structured data uh object out where you
have dduplicated and you're like very
accurate? Um you probably can train an
agent to do that well. U but we have a
data extraction agent that's really good
at that already. So we've got a lot of
agents like that for specific tasks. Uh
we've got a generative workflow engine.
Let's that lets you put together these
diverse agents alongside deterministic
steps because sometimes you don't want
to use AI. Um if you're using like if
you're providing access to somebody to
uh let's say a new system, you probably
want to follow a set of deterministic
steps. Um and the system should be able
to like mix AI steps with deterministic
steps. So we let you do that and you'll
see how that works. Um that being said,
you don't need to code. There are
nontechnical people in the room. In the
previous generation, you would have to
write code to express that deterministic
logic. Uh but Emma's autopilot will just
generate those steps for you and you
just have to check the outputs. We'll
check the integration layer out. We'll
set up an integration. Um we can work
across any of your other vendors. Um and
governance comes built in. You can use
dashboards, chats, APIs, voice, um even
generative UI um to interact with any of
these AI employees. And lastly, we built
some uh preconfigured suites on all of
these layers which come pre-built with
like 500,000 AI employees for these use
cases like employee experience, sales,
customer support.
Cool. Uh in the interest of time, I'm
going to skip through the slide. Um, if
you want to take a quick picture, you're
welcome to. Um, this is your AI employee
going from a demo to something in
production. Um, and when you make the
shift from assistants to AI employees,
you're going to face issues like it's a
lot more expensive uh to launch an AI
employee compared to an assistant. Um,
we'll skip through this. Um, we have a
booth in the Zelerback Hall. If you're
interested, come talk to us. There are a
lot of people at our booth.
Awesome. Um so this is what we're going
to be building today. Um we are going to
be building two AI employees. One
sourcing AI employee that actually
searches for real candidates using
Apollo. Um inside Emma we've got
collaborations with a lot of people data
companies. So you don't actually have to
bring your own API keys. You can
directly like use search over very large
databases that stay alive. But for this
workshop we want you to actually
integrate to a new thing. So let's do
Apollo. Next we'll do screening. Um and
here the key part to show is uh the
human in the loop. When you have AI
employees doing things end to end, you
don't want them to do like sensitive
stuff without talking to humans. So
we're going to model that. Like after I
shortlist someone, I actually want a
human to approve it before I send. So
let's see how Emma models that. And then
if you have a 100 AI employees, you
don't want the humans to be remembering
what agent does what, what AI employee
does what, whom do I go talk to. Nobody
wants to deal with routing in their
heads. So we're going to build a single
orchestrator layer across all of these
that a recruiter or hiring manager can
talk to and they don't even have to know
their different AI employees in the
background. They just have one point of
contact, a recruiting orchestrator, and
they only talk to it while the
orchestrator can talk to a lot of
different AI employees.
Cool. I think with that, let me skip
this again in the interest of time. Once
again, we'll do a quick check on access.
Um, some of you who already signed up
should have started receiving emails um
with access to the product.
Um, I'm going to quickly call on Anika.
Um, have accesses started rolling out.
They're rolling out. Okay.
Come again.
>> Sign up.
>> Um, okay. In case you're receiving an
email, I would say go to app.mr.ai
and uh just put in that same email and
you should be able to log in with an
OTP.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Um, can I get Shivven So on this? It
looks like I don't know if there's a
deployment happening or something. Um,
people are trying to log in.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay. We're going to give them two
minutes. Um, what's new for Emma is we
have these tenants be super secure with
like just uh a company specific domains
allowed. So, this is the first time we
doing stuff like atgmail.com and like
100 different domains on the same
tenant.
Okay. Uh, I'm going to give them a
second to set this up. Um and hopefully
in the next five minutes we're all
unblocked to start building.
Meanwhile, um we can go over the couple
of slides that we were planning to skip.
Um
so u Emma has three types of builders.
We've got our own builder team that goes
and works with our clients especially
super nontechnical clients like
healthcare clients etc to understand
their processes and workflows um and
helps them take it to the market. Um the
second model is we've got partners so
people like Vipro KPMG etc where the
builders are training on Emma and then
taking use cases to market. The third
one is where customers themselves do it
with Emma autopilot. Um, in each of
these cases, we recommend going through
a scoping process. For this workshop,
we've kind of pre-done it for you. We've
put it in the uh prompts and the builder
hands-on guide that you'll see. Uh, but
this is what we recommend going through
when you're actually building an AI
employee. The first one is just
discovering and scoping which parts you
want to automate, especially with AI.
So, what does the role actually require?
Uh, decomposing the job into tasks. um
and checking which ones you want to do
with AI, which ones you want to do
deterministically versus which ones you
actually want to still keep with a
human. Um we make sure to get past
examples. Something we've seen is um
people getting use cases without actual
test data sets and then you're kind of
making up the test data set as you go as
a builder who doesn't actually
understand the builder uh the business
process.
Uh the second one is integrations. Um
like I said figuring out what methods
you want to use for Emma inside Emma we
um for production use cases always
recommend directly using the APIs. If
you want you can then use MCPS which are
probably going to be slightly slower and
take up more of your context so more
expensive as well. Uh if you don't have
either of these some systems don't have
APIs or MCPS uh then we move on to
browser use within Emma. Um, and then of
course you've got retrieval for
improving your context.
Um, and then figuring out how you
actually break this up into smaller
agents so that they're easier to
evaluate, easier to maintain. You can
delegate their maintenance to different
teams in your company and so on. The
next one is human in the loop
checkpoints. In regulated industries,
this is easier um because there are a
lot of decisions AI just cannot make. It
cannot make clinical decisions for
example. um it cannot make finance
market related decisions like placing an
order. Um but even in other um use cases
you probably want to check where
judgment human judgment is key like
recruiting. You do not want agents to be
recruiting end to end. Um and then you
put a human boundary at the final act
step where you're changing the state and
you don't do it at the think step. You
actually get the AI employee to do
everything until the human actually has
to act. So they can see the notes and
decide to act. Uh the last one, yeah,
just training the agent to also
proactively um brace uh human in the
loop requests and actually ask humans uh
when it's confused.
Um quickly checking in uh with the room
on the side. Are we seeing accesses roll
out? Nope. Okay, that's unfortunate. Uh
okay cool. Uh if the team figures that
out we'll keep access open the next two
three hours uh post the workshop so you
can uh play with it. Regardless we will
reach out on your emails with temporary
access. I know people are here because
they wanted to play with the product.
Um, so we plan to remove access at the
end of the workshop, but we'll keep it
open for whoever signed up. Um, for the
rest of the duration we have with you, I
can anyhow go ahead and demo the flow.
Um, probably take 15 minutes and we can
open up to questions.
Cool. Um, if you had logged in, you
would not see any of these because these
are new AI employees. because I'm going
to show you this from scratch. Let me
just delete the ones I already have
and we will restart here.
Cool. So, you're seeing um a restricted
version of the platform here. This is
what you would get access to. Um you
won't see any administration governance
settings here. Um, this is our homepage.
You'll see we have Emma Autopilot that
actually is live across all of your
different pages. Um, it has context on
who you are, what you can do, um, and
what is open in Emma in the specific
page you're on. Uh, the pages you have
access to are apps. We're not opening up
app building access. We actually do
custom UIs, custom apps, um, that you
can deploy on a new URL as well. Um,
these can have generative UI um, and so
on. We're not going to be doing that. AI
employees. You can see this is an empty
page. Um most customers here have
hundreds of different AI employees.
We're going to be building these right
now. And next one is integrations.
You'll see access to um a pre-built
integration catalog where I believe we
already do have Apollo. Uh but we're
going to be building one from scratch.
So this one has 31 different tools. Uh
but we'll build one just for our use
case so you can see how easy it is. Um,
you can see again 30 different tools.
Um, and this can come from MCP where
they don't have MCP. Just bring the
APIs.
I'm going to jump into the builder
guide.
And what we're going to do here is ask
it to create a new Apollo integration.
We're not really providing any
documentation. It's going to go to the
web, figure this out. Um, I've given it
some clues on what tools I want. I want
search people and enrich people. You can
actually skip this when you play and
you'll just see it takes like 5 10
minutes more because it's working with
you to figure what do you want to
actually do with Apollo. Um, let me zoom
in. Yeah. Then we're going to ask it uh
for a sourcing AI employee and a
screening AI employee like the ones that
I showed you earlier and an orchestrator
that uses both of these. So a recruiter
does not have to understand them. We're
going to ask it to go ahead and test on
its own. So create test CVs and job
descriptions
um and actually come up with eval
providing a data set. So, I'm going to
copy paste all of this into
our autopilot.
Um, I think a lot of the research folks
or people building agents would be
familiar with agentic harnesses um at
this point. So, I'm just going to
approve the plan. Um, this is a harness
where it's got hundreds of tools across
the Emma product infrastructure that I
showed you, the governance layers, the
builder layers, the UI layers. Um, and
then it also lets you bring your own
tools and skills. So, most companies
then enhance it with domain specific
skills. So, if you're a KPMG, you're
probably bringing in your finance
knowledge from decades uh while having
the agentic platform knowledge come in
straight from Emma.
Um so it's gone ahead created an
integration. Um
am I self-correcting? So when whenever
it fails um it actually learns from
those failures um first for the user and
then across the entire company. So this
is something we've seen really improves
the stickiness of Emma over a few months
especially when you're bringing your own
tools. um agents might not always know
um how to use those tools, but like four
or five people use it, the next hundred
people it's going to work well. Uh so
it's asking me if I've connected the API
key. Our builder doc actually has a
sample API key just set up for this
workshop. Um I'm going to go ahead to
integrations here and we see Apollo. So
I'm going to connect with my API key.
And I'm going to tell it the API key is
connected. So you'll see one thing you
literally cannot do with Emma is give
your API key here. Um it won't be able
to do anything with it. Uh so there is
no way it can actually get it connected,
paste it in. Um we do PII and sensitive
data obiscation at source. So as soon as
you put it in the chat, it actually get
offiscated and that's how it's used
downstream in the rest of the systems.
Um, so like unlike a lot of other
harnesses where people just paste API
keys and that actually works end to end,
um, we've got like strict system guard
rails against that at Emma.
Cool. So, it's got two AI employees up.
Uh, it's actually testing the tools out.
And we can go in here and actually see
the tests it's running. It's probably
running them from the background. Okay.
Still setting these up.
Um you get to see three different types
of AI employees here. The first one is
chat. Um where you can just chat with
it. Second one is a dashboard AI
employee and this is what I mentioned
earlier when I said u these are really
popular. these lead to like 90% of the
invocations because these can be invoked
via apps, via APIs or on schedules. So
you'll see that um it's single shot um
it can have multiple different steps in
the inputs. Um we've added a candidate
CV and a job description and this is
actually paused for human review. So I
can go ahead um review like the decision
etc. get more information here and
whenever I'm ready with the information
I can run it end to end to see um fit
scores uh whether the email was ready
and so on.
Cool. Um so we've seen these AI
employees get created. Um, I'm going to
quickly do a quick check myself on
access. Access is off. Okay.
Um, can you upgrade me to admin on this
on the Berkeley
done?
And then I can also quickly show you
some of the governance features.
Yep,
there we go. I'm going to quickly check.
Yep.
Okay, I just all of you are in. I think
um we just have to figure out something
on the login flow. Um
on the um admin front, on the governance
front, I can give you a quick overview.
Um analytics is what we would all expect
it to be. Um but because um Emma is a
partner customer-led company where
people are bringing their own use cases
uh we actually let companies create
subtenants and new deployments of Emma
right from here. Uh so you probably saw
when I was switching tenants that I can
actually create new deployments for each
customer and a lot of our partners use
this to deploy Emma to hundreds of their
own customers. Uh we come in with again
self-s serve settings for pretty much
login uh whitelisting email domains. You
can bring your own licenses if you've
got custom models or if you've um got
free credits. Um
this is your standard API keys and
launching M externally. Um and we come
with some pretty strong ourback and
governance features. Um previously
before autopilot most people built AI
employees manually. So I would have to
actually build a recruiting
orchestrator.
Um but
now um Emma is able to do all of this
using autopilot.
Cool. Um while we sort out the access
issues, I'm going to take a quick pause
here for questions. Um, we've got a few
more slides and content on what you can
do on this platform beyond your first
deployment that I just showed. Um, but
before I go there, any questions? Yep.
The pricing model. Um, it's usage and
outcome based pricing. Um, so for a lot
of AI employees, we are where we are
actually selling outcomes. Uh, like how
many of your employee experience tickets
are never going to go to humans? they're
going to get deflected by AI. We price
per outcome. So it might be things like
per sales proposal, per customer support
ticket, per employee experience quiry.
And sometimes it's usage based where
someone is just buying a million credits
and they're saying, I'm going to build
on Emma myself. So I might build
whatever I want for any use case.
>> Yeah,
>> it is fully self-s served. So that's
kind of the point of autopilot. There is
nothing on the UI that you can't also do
from the autopilot here. Um so um yeah,
like most of our customers are now able
to build and maintain at the same
quality that we could two years ago.
Yep.
>> We are um we're interacting with both
private integration deployments. So like
structured data behind your HubSpot,
Salesforce, Service Now um and also
unstructured data that you probably have
in Confluence, notion and so on. All of
those are brought into Emma frequently.
>> Spreadsheets as well. Yeah, like finance
use case spreadsheets are kind of the
primary mode. Yeah.
>> Hello. How do you go about ROI
measurement as your customers?
>> ROI measurement. It's a really good
question. For some use cases, especially
cost center use cases, it's pretty
straightforward. Uh it's um fewer hours
and fewer involvement from like the
actual humans that you used to do the
task before. Um in some other cases
where you're measuring productivity, for
example, how much faster are you um in
putting out sales proposals? That's a
common use case for us. um we start with
a prediction like I remember 2024 the
prediction was they'll get 15% faster 15
over the course of the year and then we
had to actually do studies to see how
much faster they got and within a couple
of months they were 3x faster even when
they were tenured for 10 years in the
role um so you measure um and of course
you look at the outcome which is you
have to be getting more sales proposals
like 20% more sales proposals with the
same number of people um so yeah ROI I
usually gets measured in those two
points.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, thank you for the talk. Um, how do
you think about processes that change
over time? And so in your enterprise
deployments, new regulation comes out,
new process documents, how easy is it to
reflect that in the employees that are
doing the work, the AI employees,
>> uh, the prices of models like token
pricing?
>> No, no, the process changes.
>> The process. Okay.
>> Yeah. like how quick and easy is it when
a new regulation, a new
>> something comes out?
>> Yeah, that's a really good question. Um,
they're mostly like two kinds of
changes. You see, um,
yeah, you see large changes where you
know something has changed. For example,
with prior authorization, the clinical
policies actually change every year. So,
there's a publish date where you know
it's going to change um, and it's
predictable. In those cases, it's fairly
self-s served. people can come just talk
to autopilot um Emma has versioning
people then like have a new version do
their evals and push it out but there's
a lot of real world drift that you can't
predict like your customers have started
asking new types of questions in the
last couple of weeks that you could not
predict uh for that MI is again able to
go through your audit logs identify
those opportunities for improvements um
autopilot can recommend those changes
with the right eval data to show it's
actually better and this is not going to
regress your past use cases and then a
human actually signs off on the
deployment.
Both of those are automated processes.
>> Uh question about uh can you bring these
AI employee agents integrated directly
into a zoom call or teams call and have
them interact directly.
>> Uh we haven't actually done live call
tracking yet. We've done like processing
right after the call with transcripts.
Um, but that's not a use case that's
come up yet for us.
>> Oh, a lot of questions. Um, just gonna
take a quick note to the team there. Um,
Sh
Yeah. So, fantastic presentation,
fantastic platform. This is sort of an
adjacent question about like how much
control do I have over the reward
functions for each individual agentic
employee in so far as I'm thinking about
this as a broad reinforcement learning
problem of my organization and the
individuals within it like how granular
and where is the control associated with
that?
>> Yeah, that's a really good question. Um,
and you're right that people want to get
control over the most granular step for
each AI employee, first of all, which is
why you have AI employees as opposed to
one universal agent that does everything
in your enterprise. Um, for each AI
employee, it's usually a very different
person managing it, training it, like
all of those are different roles like
the builder, the admin, the reviewer,
the onboarder. Um and like there's
usually somebody in some country who's
now tasked with this AI employee needs
to perform well for this specific use
case and those permissions are reflected
in the system. Um a lot of people run
evals at an AI employee level. Um you
don't have to be technical. Again the
control you have is specifying your use
cases. Some uh business users do it very
nontechnically. For example, they bring
last one year's tickets and they're
like, I want at least this performance
over all these tickets. Some people are
fairly technical and they actually have
eval beds. So, we support that entire
spectrum. And now within the AI employee
as well, some of these AI employees are
very free form. Uh they don't really
have a workflow. Um some of these
actually have smaller blocks and then
you can run the same evals at a block
level. like you can just measure and
improve how well the AI employee works
with Apollo and nothing else right just
the Apollo layer I want to get 100%
accuracy 99% accuracy so
>> hello
hi here
>> sorry I had a quick uh follow-up
question on what was asked before right
um the chatbot that you have over here
is there a way that we can integrate
that into existing messaging services
like Slack or something
that a lot of people actually use us in
Slack or Teams. Um like Vipro uses us in
Teams, Ghat and as an SDK, a floating
app icon over one of their internal
websites. So all three of those are
channels. Um so it's fairly easy. I
won't go through the entire setup right
here. Um but we are able to get even
non-technical people to do this
integration at this point of time.
Probably takes 10 minutes. Yeah.
Um,
yep.
>> Um, why are you guys multicloud? Like
what are the primary reasons and then
how do you guys connect to all those
clouds?
>> Uh, come again. Sorry.
>> You said you said the platform was
multicloud underneath. Um, I was just
wondering about the the primary reasons
for that. uh because a lot of sensitive
customers finance healthcare actually
want to be on prem. They want the
deployment to be where they already are.
They want the deployment to be airgapped
as well. Like Emma cannot actually talk
to any system including the web or any
API outside their cloud. Um and because
our customers can be on GCP or Azure, we
were multicloud from day one. So we've
got a SAS deployment. Dozens of
customers are on SAS. They really don't
care. It's like setting up notion for
yourself, right? like you don't care
about deployments. Uh but for customers
that do, we deploy on prem.
>> Um are you able to get your agents to
enforce a role-based access control to
data for an employee asking about
something?
>> Yes, absolutely. So we've got two types
of connections for integrations. Um it's
kind of an advanced feature. So I
probably switched it off here. I have.
Yeah, I can show it to you in a minute
on like a more powerful version of this
platform. But we allow two types of
connections. One would be like shared
service o, right? Where it doesn't
really care if I'm asking something or
if you are asking, it's the same access.
But for most use cases, it should
actually be user level o. So the first
time you ask the agent a question that
requires calling into let's say service
now it's going to ask you to login and
all your answers will now be with your
key which helps it not just restrict
what information you get uh but actually
like keep an audit log even in the other
system that okay Anushka asked for this
information and hence uh this
information was served to her via an MI
agent.
I'm wondering in the use cases that
you've built for different clients uh
how large the number of agents can get
like what is the largest scale that
you've built and also I was wondering if
you could share some estimate about like
how long a workflow would like take on
average to run for that large scale uh
deployment and also the cost if you
could share some estimates. Thank you.
Yeah, I probably can't share costs, but
from a number point of view, uh we've
definitely seen hundreds in a single
tenant in a single customer deployment.
Um 300, 400. I've seen that number
myself. Um the point here is also it's
in people's interest to break these up
because of the point I made earlier
about who's maintaining this, who's
responsible for this working and staying
up to date and actually following our
processes. And we are seeing that a lot
of humans are now becoming AI employee
managers. So you are tasked as somebody
who has a team of six human employees
and these three AI employees on Emma
that 200,000 people in your company
might use but you're the one responsible
for making sure this one performs well.
Um because you're the business expert on
this process, right? Um so it's in
people's interest to actually break it
down. Um the workflows can get super
complex. You can merge these. you can
break them apart, but breaking them
apart just means better governance and
management. Um, from a duration point of
view, there are workflows that take
multiple days. Uh, like you're
processing a very complex finance use
case, a new procurement for a vendor
probably has 10 approvals. Um, so it
really depends on the business process
itself. Uh, because you're getting stuck
on like the humans that are going to do
the approvals. The agent is quick, but
the real world uh implications are
there. um and a lot of other use cases
much faster.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so you mentioned proactive in your
earlier slides. How how how do you make
AI employee proactive? Like um
>> it's a good question. Um let me see if I
can pull up maybe a really messy
internal demo. Once again, this one is
very restricted, has a lot fewer
features.
Um,
okay. I'm just going to create a new
one. This is a test tenant.
I can show it to you.
So, when you've got AI employees um that
you create, they can obviously be
triggered by someone texting them. But
what we allow and once again nobody
actually looks at these screens guys you
just talk to autopilot. All of this is
like the background. It's like looking
at the code at this point. Um we let
people set up web hooks. We let uh these
AI employees pull your systems. Um we
let it connect directly to systems and
have like conditions like when there's a
new lead added to Salesforce, I want you
to go and figure out if they're a good
candidate for us. Um, so we've got a lot
of different types of triggers like
monitoring inboxes, setting up
schedules, every morning I want an email
that does X. Um, and all of these are as
simple as sending a sentence out and
these just automatically run.
>> Hey, uh, hi, I have a question about uh
earlier you showed the copilot. Yeah, it
helps uh basically self uh drive work in
a self-driving mode. But uh there might
I imagine that if you're working with
ticket resolution there might be a bunch
of things which are repeated again and
again over and over.
>> Yeah.
>> So does it also offer basically pre pre
uh basically pre-built code recipes so
that deterministic tasks can be done
otherwise the token cost for the things
which are very maintained in nature
would just keep on keep on.
>> Yeah absolutely. So uh we let people
actually represent uh code specifically
as a part of workflows as well.
>> Um the thing is you don't want to spend
months setting this up. So what you can
actually start with is an empty MR
tenant zero AI employees and you're just
working with Emma autopilot for every
task and as it figures what's repetitive
it starts codifying those. Um, so it
builds AI employees which are agentic or
actually straight up writes code and
maintains that based on real world usage
and feedback.
Awesome.
>> Thank you for the talk, Anushka. Very,
very cool. Thank you for making it
detailed enough to be useful. Um,
question that I have for you is more
meta. You're positioning this as AI
employees and that would imply sort of
discrete or transformational business
process outsourcing. The whole business
process is outsourced. But a lot of your
examples are more task oriented. What
would you say the distribution is
between like a true offshore but now
it's a digital shore outsourcing versus
task specific within a employees broader
span of responsibilities. So task versus
full business process
>> right um the end state for every
contract and project we start with is
role focused right. Um so it usually
ends up in a single interface you can
talk to which can actually do the entire
job or a single automation that can
actually do the entire job across all of
the different tasks. Um the adoption
usually starts a little slower. So what
we see is you can build an AI employee
that does everything end to end. Um but
the blocker is always the humans that
are collaborating with that AI employee.
Um so we've seen like actually launching
them task by task. So let's start with
sourcing then let's start then move on
to screening the CVS and then let's move
on to scheduling the interviews with the
candidate and then let's move on to
onboarding the candidates you actually
liked managing the offer letter etc.
usually helps the recruiting team like
slowly warm up and learn how to work
with AI agents better um so you start
with a task and you like expand to the
entire gamut of what that role can do.
>> Yeah. Hey um what are the typical uh
ratios between a human and their um AI
employees? So if I have a company of 20
humans,
what is the typical ratio of number of
you know agents they would have and then
what is the farthest you have seen? In
other words, one human with 100 agents
for example,
>> right? Um it's really easy and cheap to
create new AI employees in Emma. you
only get charged when you're actually
getting value out of it. Um, so a lot of
people do go ahead and create a lot of
these automations, but Emma works with
very large companies. We don't work with
small and medium enterprises. So the
ratio is always going to be um very
large recruiting team, 200 people, but
they only ever need like maybe 20 uh AI
employees and that's what everybody
works with. So the usage per AI employee
is very very high, thousands of
invocations per day. Um but we don't
really optimize for number of agents.
>> Hey
>> I have a question for you more on the
practical side as many said before
really good presentation. I really like
the aspect we hear a lot about the
technology and what makes it work in the
background but how do you apply it in
the real world so so really really well
done. This was a good context. I want to
go even more practical. Let's say you
win a big deal with General Motors or
Bank of America to do all of their
processes, right? How does it really
work? When you go in, you ask them for
their process books. How do you onboard
a new employee or you sit beside
somebody and somebody who does this job
day by day would do it? This is my first
question. And then the second one, what
I would assume you will get a lot of
resistance maybe from some people,
right? Why would I use this tool? And
people are not dumb, right? Hey, will
they do my job? How do you deal with
this resistance and and how do you get
in into the this aspect?
>> Yeah, those are good questions and that
uh definitely happens in real life. So
um to the first question, the deployment
um process models that I talked about
earlier, it's either um someone at Emma
or one of our partners that has become
the agentic transformation expert and is
responsible for the AI employees working
well and launching them the first time.
In that case, it's like a deep discovery
process, right? um where you're actually
not just doing workshops with the buyer
and the team lead, but you're sitting in
the room with the person doing the job
and shadowing them for hours and days.
Um you're looking at all the past
examples of their work from the last one
year. Um and then coming up with the
definition. Once you have the process
well defined, you don't have to do much.
You can throw it into Emma autopilot a
few hours and it's built and tested. So
you don't have to know about Emma to
launch impactful stuff in Emma. You have
to know a lot about the business
process. That's expertise you need. Um,
but like I said, like this is also a
very common model where a lot of our
customers then move on to wanting to
build themselves. Uh, so they're like,
if you're just going to put it in Ma
Autopilot, I can do that. Um, I'm the
expert on this recruiting process. Just
give me access. And then they go ahead
and play around. And we're seeing the
rise of citizen developers like people
who really want to bring AI into their
jobs uh without being technical at all.
They've never written a line of code in
their lives. Um to the second point, I
feel like that resistance was a lot more
common a couple of years ago, two three
years ago where it was like, hey, why do
you want me to evaluate AI samples when
this will probably affect my own role?
Um we've seen that change a lot in the
last couple of years. Everyone's
realized you need to be faster and AI
equipped to stay at the top of your job,
to stay at the top of your industry, and
adopting AI will actually make you more
indisposable and much better at your
job. So we see a lot of excitement where
people want to be the ones training it,
want to understand how it actually works
and get deeper. Now
uh hello everyone. Thank you so much for
your patience. You should be able to
sign in now um and be your own citizen
developer. So yeah, please try out our
platform. We'll extend access beyond the
session as well. Uh so now your emails
should work.
>> Yeah, sorry about that. Um
but yes, please log in. Um paste out
this prompt. Uh play with it. Build your
own integration. Uh do not connect any
real systems, please. This is a shared
tenant. Do not connect your customers or
your own data. Uh your companies won't
like that. I've pasted um an Apollo API
key. I'll increase the number of uh
credits on this um so you can use it
through the day. Um yeah, go ahead and
play with it. Um, and we have a booth
once again like I mentioned in Zelerbach
Mezzanine. So if you try it out and you
have feedback or you have questions,
we're all going to be there the rest of
the day. So you can come talk to us um
ask us more questions.
Um, and also last thing, we've never
actually opened this up um to people
without a contract, right? Like we've
got very large customers, they keep us
busy. Uh, but we are opening up for free
selfserve trial access end of this
month. um I think you would have marked
it on the form but if you have signed up
for that you can actually get slightly
longerterm access than one day to Emma
to actually try and automate stuff.
Um I see we're almost done with the
session. This was all the time I had.
I'm slightly over. Um can we go over for
a couple more questions? Should we wrap
up here?
>> One or two more. Okay. Can probably take
one or two. Yeah.
>> Uh it's again like the two models when
we are taking outcomes um to the market
with customer. Uh it is based on the use
case like a sales proposal use case is
going to be priced very differently from
a customer support use case. Does not
depend on the number of tokens being
used. It's not cost based pricing. It's
about like how much you would actually
pay a person in that job and how much
faster are we making them. So some jobs
just cost a lot more. Uh we actually
instrument those outcome based pricing
models in tandem with customers and our
metrics billing metrics are extremely
configurable. So when you take AI
employees for sales proposal to market
you will actually measure the number of
sales proposals price based on that.
Yeah, that's the last question.
Uh, so skills is like a less powerful
version of an AI employee. We let you do
that too in the system. Um, the benefit
this has is we actually have like a
strong template marketplace. These are
templates that allow people to share
stuff with the right people in their own
company very easily. So you can use that
for skills, you can use that for AI
employees. But like I mentioned earlier,
EI employees are a lot more complex.
They've got their own memory. They've
got deterministic and non like agentic
steps put in there and they have eva
they are being evaluated for that use
case very very well. Um and most people
who are taking something live actually
want all of these tabs. They want to see
how many people used it, where it went
wrong, where can I improve, I want auto
improvement help and so on. Um, so even
though skills does exist on the
platform, most people prefer using AI
employees directly.
Cool. Thank you so much. That was
all righty. Thank you, Emma. So, it's
lunchtime now. We have lunches in
Stevens, which is the corner room. It's
like a wooden room. Also, we have
lunches in the lower Sprawl Plaza and
then posters and presentations on the
first floor. And we'll return at 1:00.
So, 50 minutes and one o'clock return
here on Atlas. Thank you.